To understand what I'm about to tell
you, you need to do something first,
you need to believe
in the impossible.
Can you do that? Good.
You see that red blur?
That's me.
That too.
There I am again.
My name is Barry Allen.
I am the fastest man alive.
My story is pretty simple.
My whole life,
I have been running.
Usually from bullies.
Sometimes I escaped.
Sometimes I did not.
Tell me what happened.
Those guys were picking on kids Just
'cause they thought they weren't cool.
- It wasn't right.
- I know.
- I guess I wasn't fast enough.
- No.
You have such a good heart,
Barry.
And it's better to have a
good heart than fast legs.
Hello. I'm home.
- Barry got into a fight.
- Oh, yeah?
And he won.
Way to go, Slugger.
And, no more fighting.
But after that night, I was running
from something much scarier.
- Something I could never explain.
- Henry! Henry!
Something impossible.
Help!
- Mom!
- Barry, don't!
- Don't let him touch you!
Mom!
- Nora!
- Stay back!
Nora, hold on!
Run, Barry, run!
Mom?
Dad?
Sorry.
Second robbery this week.
The teller ID'd Clyde
Mardon as the shooter.
What?
Oh, Geez,
the Mardon brothers are back.
What do we got?
Perps took the bank,
shot out the cameras,
and as a chaser, killed the
security guard over there.
I've got unis kicking in doors of
known Mardon brothers associates.
CSI been over it?
No.
Where's Allen?
Sorry! Sorry.
You can't keep
covering for him...
- CSI! CSI! Coming through.
- If he's not here now,
I'm gonna have to carry on
this investigation without him.
Sorry I'm late, Captain Singh.
What was it this time,
Mister Allen?
Did you forget to
set your alarm clock?
Before you answer,
I should remind you,
the excuse you gave last
time was car trouble.
Wanna know why that one
was particularly memorable?
I do not own a car.
He was running an errand for me.
Barry,
did you get me what I asked for?
Yeah. Yeah, I did.
I have it right...
here.
I had a few bites of it.
Getaway car is a
Mustang Shelby GT-500.
Shelby's have a rear super-wide
tire specific to that model.
12 inches with an
asymmetrical tread.
And there's something else.
Thanks.
Fecal excrement.
Animal, I'd guess.
My dad gave me that pen.
Before he died.
Sorry.
Ok! I am ready to see this
atom smasher smashing.
There was a shooting today.
Your dad needs me to
process some evidence,
which means I don't know if we're going
to be able to make it to S.T.A.R. labs.
But seeing this thing turn
on is like your dream.
Your sad, little nerdy dream.
Besides,
I canceled a date for this.
Hands off my fries.
Unbelievable.
I'm stress-eating
over my dissertation.
We started selling
cronuts at jitters.
I ate two today.
If I don't graduate soon,
I'm gonna be more
muffin top than woman.
You look amazing.
What is so important about this
particle accelerator anyway?
Harrison Wells'
work in quantum theory
is light-years ahead of
anything they're doing at CERN.
You're doing that thing where
you're not speaking English.
Okay.
Just imagine
that that dot is everything the human
race has ever learned until this moment.
Does that include twerking?
That is everything we could learn
from the particle accelerator.
It's a whole new way
of looking at physics.
It will literally change the way
that we think about everything.
You got to get
yourself a girlfriend.
Hey, leave him alone.
He's working.
Hi, Dad.
- Your test thingy is done.
- Yeah.
I think the Mardon brothers
are hiding on a farm.
The fecal matter I found on
the street, it was cow manure,
which contains traces
of oxytetracycline.
It's an antibiotic.
There are only four
farms in the area
in the area that still
use it in their feed.
Bet you find a really sweet
Shelby parked at one of them.
Dad, seeing as how barry
solved your poop problem,
how about letting him
go to S.T.A.R. labs?
- Fine, go.
- Yes!
Thank you, Joe.
So Barry, how was your trip?
Did you find proof of the
impossible in Starling City,
or did you just make my
dad mad for no reason?
Actually, while I was away,
I had a chance to think about...
you know, relationships.
And, well, I'm not in one.
And you're not in one, either.
And you're my best friend, Iris.
You're mine, too.
Why else would I be here?
That's not what I meant.
What I meant...
I know what you're gonna say,
Barry.
I'm not sure you do.
Even though we pretty much grew
up in the same house together,
and we're kind of like
brother and sister,
because we're not
it can get really weird and
awkward to talk to me about girls.
But I just want you to know
that it shouldn't be awkward.
There is nothing that I want more
than for you to meet the right person
that totally loves and adores you
for the amazing guy that you are.
Took the words right
out of my mouth.
Aren't you glad I
know you so well?
Thank you.
My name is Harrison Wells.
Tonight, the future begins.
The work my team and I will do here will
change our understanding of physics.
We'll bring about advancements in
power, advancements in medicine.
And trust me, that future will
be here faster than you think.
Hey, my laptop!
It's got my dissertation.
I'm sorry.
All right, kid, you don't
have to do this, all right?
Just give me back my friend's
bag, and we'll call it even.
Okay?
Barry!
- Are you ok?
- Yeah.
Freeze! Police!
Or do you want to find out the hard
way you're not faster than a bullet?
Who is that guy,
and what is he so proud of?
So he caught a mugger?
He's a transfer from Keystone.
Started a few weeks ago.
Eddie Thawne.
Oh, that's Detective Pretty Boy.
That's what my dad calls him.
Says he actually keeps score
when it comes to arrests.
He is pretty though.
This is the last
farm on Barry's list.
Look, I know the kid's smart,
but you said it yourself?
Sometimes he's
chasing flying pigs.
Well, let's check it out anyway.
I'm Linda Park, and we're
live outside S.T.A.R. Labs.
Despite the inclement weather,
which is only going to get worse.
The torrential downpour has in no way
affected the particle accelerator,
which is up and running smoothly
according to S.T.A.R. Labs
CEO Harrison Wells.
The weather has also...
Mardon.
I've got a plane to catch!
What the hell?
Chyre, hang in there.
Wait, we are now being told
to evacuate the facility.
The storm may have caused a malfunction
to the primary cooling system.
Officials are now trying to shut down
the particle accelerator, but so far,
have been unable to regain
control of the system...
What the hell happened to him?
He was hit by lightning.
How is he still alive?
Go!
No heartbeat. CBC, chem 24,
type and cross four. Bag him.
- Coding!
- Flatlined.
- You can't be in here!
- I'm family!
- Charge the paddles to 200.
- Barry!
Clear!
What are you doing?
He likes this song.
How could you
possibly know that?
I checked his Facebook page.
I mean,
he can hear everything, right?
Auditory functions are the last
sensory faculties to degenerate.
Can't read my...
No he can't read my poker face
- Oh, my God!
- Where am I?
He's up!
Doctor Wells, get down to
the cortex, like right now.
Pulse 120, pupils equally
reactive to light.
- Look at me. Look at me.
- Hey hey. Oh, oh, relax.
Everything's ok, man.
You're at S.T.A.R. Labs.
S.T.A.R. Labs?
Who... who are you?
I'm Cisco Ramon.
She's Caitlin... Dr. Snow.
I need you to urinate in this.
Not this second.
What... what is happening?
What is going on?
You were struck by lightning,
dude.
Lightning gave me abs?
Your muscles should be atrophied,
but instead they're in a chronic
And unexplained state of
cellular regeneration.
Come here, have a seat.
You were in a coma.
For how long?
Nine months.
Welcome back, mister Allen.
We have a lot to discuss.
It's hard to believe I'm here.
I've always wanted to
meet you face to face.
Yeah?
Well, you certainly went
to great length to do it.
S.T.A.R. Labs has
not been operational
since FEMA categorized us as
a class 4 hazardous location.
17 people died that night.
Many more were injured.
Myself amongst them.
Geez.
What happened?
Nine months ago,
the particle accelerator
went online exactly as planned.
For 45 minutes,
I had achieved my life's dream.
And then...
then there was an anomaly.
The electron volts became
unmeasurable, the ring under us popped.
Energy from that detonation
was thrown into the sky
and that,
in turn seeded a storm-cloud...
That created a lightning bolt
that struck me.
That's right.
I was recovering myself
when I heard about you.
The hospital was undergoing
unexplainable power outages.
Every time you were going
into cardiac arrest,
which was actually
a misdiagnosis
because you see,
you weren't flat-lining, Barry,
your heartbeat was moving too
fast for the EKG to register it.
Now, I'm not the most popular
person in town these days,
but detective west and his daughter
gave me permission to bring you here,
where we were able
to stabilize you.
- Iris?
- Iris, yes.
She came to see you quite often.
She talks a lot.
Also, she's hot.
- I need to go.
- No, you can't.
No, no, no, Caitlin's right, now that
you're awake, we need to do more tests.
You're still going
through changes.
There's so much
that we don't know.
I'm fine, really. I feel normal.
Thank you for saving my life.
Really?
Can I keep the sweatshirt?
- Yeah, keep the sweatshirt.
- Ok.
Sure.
- Fill 'er up?
- Thanks.
Oh, my God.
You're awake.
Why didn't S.T.A.R.
Labs call us?
I just woke up.
Should you even be on your feet?
Iris, I-I'm okay.
I watched you die, Barry.
You kept dying.
Your heart kept stopping.
It's still beating.
- Feels really fast.
-Oops.
Are you okay, Tracy?
Yeah, I got it.
My dad is gonna be
so happy to see you.
Let me get my stuff, okay?
Be right back.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
How can I help you today?
"This is a robbery."
Is this supposed to be a joke?
You tell me.
Oh, you scared the
hell out of us, kid.
Yeah, that was quite the nap you took
there, baby face, and you still look 12.
You look okay.
Are you really?
- Yeah.
- Detective West,
We've got a 5.15 in progress
at gold city bank, two dead.
Storm's really picking
up on the south side.
I'd grab your rain gear.
I'm sorry, Barry. I got to run.
- Do you need my help?
- No, you take it easy.
There'll be plenty for you
to do once you settle in.
Let's go, partner.
Hey, Allen. Glad to see you.
- Thanks, Eddie.
- Hey, Iris.
Detective, you should go.
My dad doesn't like
to be kept waiting.
Glad you're back.
The night of the explosion, Clyde
Mardon shot and killed Chyre.
Mardon and his brother
died trying to escape.
Their plane crashed.
Iris, got a minute?
Hey, Barry. Good to see you.
Screw you!
You okay?
I-I'm fine.
I-I just need some air.
But I'll call you tonight,
all right?
What's happening to me?
Awesome.
You don't really believe he
can run that fast, do you?
Well, I believe anything is
possible, and in a few minutes,
maybe you will too.
How does it fit?
It's a little snug.
At least you will be moving
so fast no one will see you.
See, you thought the
world was slowing down.
It wasn't.
You re moving so fast, it only looked
like everyone else was standing still.
Dr. Wells will be monitoring your
energy output, and Caitlin, your vitals.
What do you do?
I make the toys, my man.
Check it.
This is a two-way headset
with a camera I modified.
Typically designed to combat
battlefield impulse noise,
or in your case, potential sonic
booms, which would be awesome.
- What?
- Nothing.
I just noticed you
don't smile too much.
My once promising career
in bioengineering is over,
my boss is in a wheelchair for life,
the explosion that put you in a coma
also killed my fiance.
So this blank expression kind
of feels like the way to go.
Mr. Allen, while I am extremely eager to
determine your full range of abilities,
I do caution restraint.
Yeah.
He just passed 200
miles per hour.
It's not possible.
Mom!
- No, Barry!
- Mom!
No! Don't let him touch you!
What is all this?
Witnesses from the
robbery at Gold City Bank.
Perp made off with 200 grand,
more or less.
- Catch these guys.
- The windows blew in.
It was like a hurricane.
Everyone ran for cover.
We're going to have a sketch artist
work with you, if you feel up to it.
Third robbery in a month
where a freak storm precedes it.
Sounds like one of those
"Wide world of weird" cases
- Barry's obsessed with.
- He's not obsessed.
Guess you haven't read his blog.
The security
cameras at the bank.
Apparently it all shorted out.
We got a bunch of
witnesses here.
They all have cell phones.
The sky went black and then,
boom.
Outside was inside.
Man, it was like there was
a thunderstorm in the bank.
Vukuvich, suspect is
driving a black Mustang.
Partial plate
Six-Kilo-Charlie-Three.
- Put out an APB.
- Copy that.
It looks like you had a
distal radius fracture.
Had?
It's healed... in three hours.
How is that even possible?
We don't know...yet.
You really need to
learn how to stop.
What happened out there today?
You were moving pretty well, and then
something caused you to lose focus.
I started remembering something.
When I was 11,
my mother was murdered.
It was late.
A sound woke me up.
I came downstairs and...
I saw what looked like
a ball of lightning.
Inside the lightning,
there was a man.
He killed my mom.
They arrested my dad.
He's still sitting in Iron
Heights for her murder.
Everyone, the cops, the shrinks, they
all told me what I saw was impossible.
But what if the man who
killed my mom was like me?
Well, I think I can say
unequivocally you are one of a kind.
Can I help you, detective?
You can stop acting like you can't
stand me when your dad's around.
And I like having a boyfriend
who isn't shot to death.
You can't tell my dad.
He doesn't know
about me and Eddie.
Doesn't seem like
anyone's in on the secret.
I was gonna tell you.
When you were in the hospital,
Eddie covered my father's shifts
so that we could
both be with you.
I thanked him with a cup of coffee,
and things just kind of happened.
And it's good.
Dating your partner's daughter...
isn't that against
department regulations?
Why are you so upset?
I just don't like having to
lie to your dad, you know?
Barry?
Hey! Mardon!
That poor man.
The way thog came in, I have
never seen anything like it.
Barry! Iris.
I'm all right, dad.
What the hell were you thinking
- having her out here?
- No, no, no...
And I told you, when you see danger,
You run the other way. You're not a cop.
- Because you wouldn't let me.
- You're damn right.
Joe, I need to talk to you.
- It can wait.
- No, now.
I know who did this.
It's Clyde Mardon.
I know everybody thinks
he died in a plane crash
after the S.T.A.R. Labs
explosion, but he is alive.
All right, something
happened to him that night.
I... I think he can
control the weather.
The recent robberies, they all happened
during freak meteorological events.
And when I just confronted Mardon, the
street was instantly enveloped in fog.
Of course you don't believe me.
- You never believe me.
- Okay.
You want to do this now?
Out here? Fine.
Mardon is dead.
There is no controlling
the weather, Barry.
Just like there was no lightning
storm in your house that night.
It was your brain helping a scared
little boy accept what he saw.
My dad did not murder my mother.
Yes, he did! Your dad
killed your mother, Barry!
I am sorry, son!
But I knew it, the jury knew it,
and now he's paying for what he did.
- Dad, enough!
- Iris.
I have done my best to take care of you
since that night, and I have never asked
for anything in return,
not even a thank you,
but what I do ask now
is that you for once
in your life see
things as they are.
You're not going
to believe this.
We got the eyewitness sketch
of the from the bank job.
If I didn't know better,
I'd say that's Clyde Mardon.
But that's impossible.
He's dead, right?
I wasn't the only one affected by the
particle accelerator explosion, was I?
We don't know for sure.
You said the city was safe, that
there was no residual danger.
But that's not true, so what
really happened that night?
The accelerator went active, we
all felt like heroes, and then,
it all went wrong.
The dimensional
barrier ruptured,
unleashing unknown
energies into our world.
Antimatter, dark energy,
X-elements...
Those are all theoretical.
And how theoretical are you?
We mapped the dispersion
throughout and around central city.
Though we have no way of
knowing exactly what or...
who was exposed, we've been searching
for other Meta-humans like yourself.
"Meta-humans"?
That's what we're calling them.
I saw one today.
He's a bank robber,
and he can control the weather.
This just keeps getting cooler.
This is not cool.
All right? A man died.
Mardon must have gotten his
powers the same way I did.
From the storm cloud.
He's still out there.
We have to stop him before
he hurts anyone else.
Barry!
That's a job for the police.
I work for the police.
As a forensic assistant.
You're responsible for this.
For him.
What's important is you!
Not me. I lost everything.
I lost my company.
I lost my reputation.
I lost my freedom.
And then you broke your arm,
and it healed in three hours.
Inside your body could be a map to a
whole new world... genetic therapies,
vaccines, medicines,
treasures buried deep
within your cells and we
cannot risk losing everything
because you want to
go out and play hero!
You're not a hero.
You are just a young man
who was struck by lightning.
I didn't do this.
I swear to god,
Dad, why are they taking you?
- Barry, don't go in the house.
- Where's mom?
What's gonna happen to my son?
- Dad!
- Barry!
- Stay out of the house!
Barry!
Joe, you know these people?
My daughter's best
friends with their kid.
I'm sorry.
- Mom.
- Barry.
Mom!
So that's my story.
I've spent my whole life searching
for the impossible, never imagining
that I would become
the impossible.
So why come to me?
Something tells me you didn't just
run 600 miles to say "Hi" to a friend.
All my life,
I've wanted to just do more...
Be more.
And now I am.
And the first chance I get
to help someone, I screw up.
What if Wells is right?
What if I'm not a hero?
What if I'm just some guy
who was struck by lightning?
I don't think that bolt of
lightning struck you, Barry.
I think it chose you.
I'm just not sure I'm like you,
Oliver.
I don't know if I can
be some...Vigilante.
You can be better.
Because you can inspire people
in a way that I never could...
Watching over your city
like a guardian angel...
making a difference...
saving people...
in a flash.
Take your own advice.
Wear a mask.
Cool.
I've been going over unsolved
cases from the past nine months,
and there's been a sharp increase in
unexplained deaths and missing people.
Your meta-humans have been busy.
Now, I'm not blaming you.
I know you didn't mean
for any of this to happen.
I know you all lost something.
But I need your help to catch Mardon
and anyone else out there like him.
But I can't do it without you.
If we're gonna do this, I have
something that might help.
Something I've
been playing with.
Designed to replace the turnouts
firefighters traditionally wear.
I thought if S.T.A.R. Labs could do
something nice for the community,
maybe people wouldn't be so
angry at Dr. Wells anymore.
How is it going to help me?
It's made of a
reinforced tri-polymer.
It's heat and abrasive resistant,
so it should withstand your moving
at high-velocity speeds.
And the aerodynamic design
should help you maintain control.
Plus, it has built-in sensors
so we can track your vitals
and stay in contact
with you from here.
Thanks.
Now how do we find Mardon?
I retasked S.T.A.R.
Labs satellite
to track meteorological
abnormalities over central city.
We just got a ping.
Atmospheric pressure dropped 20
millibars in a matter of seconds.
I've tracked it to a farm
just west of the city.
I'm not saying Mardon is alive.
But if he was, this is the last
place him and his brother hid out.
Let's go.
Mardon?
On your feet.
Hands on your head.
You got me.
The night of the storm,
after S.T.A.R. Labs blew,
after our plane went down, and
I woke up on the ground alive,
when I saw what I can do,
I understood.
I am God.
Shut the hell up.
Turn around.
Do you think that your
guns can stop God?
Why in the hell would
god need to rob banks?
You're right.
I've been thinking too small.
Barry! Barry!
This thing's getting closer.
Wind speeds are 200
miles-per-hour and increasing.
Barry, can you hear me?
Yeah. Loud and clear.
If it keeps up,
this could become an F5 tornado.
And it's headed
towards the city.
How do I stop it? Guys?
What if I unravel it?
How the hell are you
going to do that?
I'll run around it in the opposite
direction, cut off its legs.
He'd have to clock 700
miles-per-hour to do that.
Your body may not be able
to handle those speeds.
You'll die.
I have to try.
The suit's holding up.
- But he's not.
- He can do it.
I know he can do it.
It's too strong!
It's time to think big.
You can do this, Barry.
You were right.
I am responsible
for all of this.
So many people have been hurt because
of me, and when I looked at you,
all I saw was another
potential victim of my hubris.
And yes, I created this madness,
but you, Barry, you can stop it.
You can do this.
Now run, Barry, run!
Barry?
I didn't think there
was anyone else like me.
I'm not like you.
You're a murderer.
- Barry?
- It's over.
I'm okay.
What you can do...
it was the lightning bolt?
More or less.
I'm sorry, Barry.
I'm sorry I didn't believe you.
And I called you crazy for
chasing the impossible.
But you really did see something
that night your mom died.
And your dad is innocent.
I need you to
promise me something.
I don't want you telling Iris about
anything you can do, any of it.
I want her safe.
Promise me.
Yeah.
Hey, Slugger.
You've been calling me
that since I was 11.
Funny thing is, I finally
got into a fight today.
You just got out of a coma.
I'm not sure you should
be picking fights.
Did you win?
Yeah, I did.
You didn't kill mom.
You know I know that, right?
You believing me is all I need.
You're not gonna be
in here much longer.
Whoever killed mom...
whatever killed her...
I think I finally have a way
to find them, to stop them.
Barry, we've talked about this.
It's time to let it go.
You have got to stop
worrying about me,
and live your life.
For the first time,
I feel like I finally can.
The truth is, ever since the night mom
died, I've been stuck in one place,
missed out on a lot of things.
But I'm different now.
I've made some new friends.
They're helping
me find my way...
Why is it shaped like
a lightning bolt?
So it's not boring.
To finally move forward.
You remember when you
wanted me to change my name
so I wouldn't have to deal with
people knowing you're my dad?
I'm glad they know.
I'm so proud to be your son.
I love you, son.
I love you too, dad.
My name is Barry Allen,
and I am the fastest man alive.
A friend recently gave me
the idea for a new name.
And something tells me,
it's gonna catch on.